Why did Her Majesty suddenly give orders
城主為何突然下令
for you and the Crown Princess to get a divorce?
讓您和少城主和離
The envoys' visit
定是此次使者來訪
must have made her raise doubts.
讓她起了疑心
Shall we take the opportunity
那我們要不要趁此機會
to make a clear break with the Crown Princess?
與少城主劃清界限
You're Crown Prince of Xuanhu City
您是玄虎城的少城主
and she's the Crown Princess of Huayuan City.
她是花垣城的少城主
Both of you are the future City Owners.
將來都是要繼承城主之位的人
You'll have to go back to Xuanhu City sooner or later.
您終有一天要回到玄虎城
The two of you are like the general and the marshal on the Chinese chess board,
就像這棋盤上的將和帥
who can't cross the River of the Chu or the Border of the Han,
既不能越過楚河漢界
let alone meet each other.
更不能碰面
What if I remove the boundary?
如果我把這條界限消除了呢
Do you mean
您是說
we'll conquer Huayuan City?
滅掉花垣城
If the whole Chinese chess board is yours,
如果整個棋盤都是您的
then the Crown Princess
那少城主
will definitely belong to you.
自然逃不過您的手掌心
Young Master,
少君
we're from Xuanhu City, anyway.
我們畢竟是玄虎城的人
Her Majesty has ordered
城主有令
we should strengthen public security now that Xuanhu City's envoys are here.
玄虎使者來訪 需加強巡防
Stay alert.
大家都警醒著點
Lord Han,
韓大人
we're doing this without letting Young Master know.
我們這樣瞞著少君行事
Will he punish us
被他知道了
if he knows about it?
會不會治我們的罪呀
We're doing it under the orders of the City Owner.
我們是奉城主的命令行事
Young Master also needs to listen to his father.
少君還不是得聽城主的
Got it.
是是是
Be careful.
小心點你
It's all explosives inside.
這裡面全是炸藥
Qianqian,
芊芊
why does Han Shuo still stay in your mansion?
你怎麼還沒有讓韓爍出府
I've told you to divorce him.
我不是令你和他和離嗎
Mother,
母親 你就
please give me more time.
再多給我點時間吧
I don't know why you're into him.
也不知道你喜歡他什麼
In terms of appearance, moral quality or talent,
論長相 論人品 論才情
Pei Heng is all superior.
哪一點都是裴恆更勝一籌
Well. It's not a beauty pageant.
不是 這又不是在選美
I really don't love Pei Heng.
我是真的不喜歡裴司學
I can understand why Han Shuo misunderstood me. You...
韓爍誤會我就罷了 你
Your Majesty, let me pay my respects.
見過城主
You'd better not make trouble.
你就別瞎搗亂了
Han Shuo,
韓少君
please take a seat.
請坐
Thank you, Your Majesty.
多謝城主
Qianqian.
芊芊
I'm going to give my regards to your mother.
我去向城主請安
Go ahead.
去吧 去吧 去吧
Qianqian.
芊芊
This year,
今年
you'll still get the most prey, right?
應該還是你手中的獵物最多吧
Why?
為什麼
In previous years,
往年圍獵
the Second Princess sent most of her prey
二郡主射中的獵物
to your mansion.
大都送到你府上
Yeah. Chuchu loves me most.
是 二姐最寵我了
Qianqian has been unruly and self-willed since childhood
芊芊自小刁蠻任性
and Pei Heng is gentle and cultivated.
而裴恆卻溫文爾雅
He'll be the most tolerant one towards her.
最能包容芊芊的一切了
If the two of them get married,
如果日後兩人成婚
they'll be a happy couple
肯定會成為花垣城
everyone admires.
人人稱羨的一對
Pitifully...
可惜了
Pitifully, Qianqian has married me.
可惜少城主已經與我成婚了
Han Shuo,
韓少君
men in Xuanhu are different from those in Huayuan.
玄虎城和花垣城男人有所不同
In Xuanhu City, a woman is required to
玄虎城講的女人
obey her father before marriage, her husband when married, and her sons in widowhood.
是未嫁從父 既嫁從夫 夫死從子
In short, men are in authority over women.
男人就是天
It's just the opposite in Huayuan.
而在花垣城正好是相反
Here, men are appendages to women.
男人就是女人的附屬品
Are you sure
你確定
you're willing to become Qianqian's appendage?
甘願成為芊芊的附屬品嗎
Qianqian, don't feel awkward.
芊芊 你不必為難
I hope
我希望
we can get along as before.
我們還是像以前一樣相處
As
像
friends?
朋友一樣
Can you try to persuade my mother?
那你能不能出面去勸勸母親啊
Just tell her you regret it
就說 你後悔了
and you don't want to marry me.
不願意跟我成親
She wouldn't listen to me.
我跟她說她都不肯聽我的
Only if you insist on refusing to marry me
只有你堅持拒婚
can she give up that idea.
才能打消她這個念頭的
What if I say
可如果我說
I don't want to reject it?
我不想拒絕呢
You just said
你剛剛不是還說
we could get along as friends.
我們可以像朋友一樣相
I also said I'd wait.
我也說過 我會等
Alright.
好了
I mean
我是說
I'll wait for the right time
我會等一個合適的機會
to talk about it with your mother.
和城主提及此事
Really?
真的
You haven't come out hunting for a long time.
你許久不曾出來圍獵
Have a good time today.
今天 就先玩個盡興吧
I...
我
I won't let this thing worry you.
我不會讓你因為此事為難
Thank you, Pei Heng.
謝謝你 裴恆
Qianqian and I love each other.
我和芊芊兩情相悅
I'm not an appendage to her and vice versa.
沒有誰是誰的附屬品一說
You said you loved each other.
你說的兩情相悅
How will you prove
不知你拿什麼證明
your love for Qianqian?
你對芊芊的情意呢
You must have got an idea.
城主早有決斷了吧
According to rituals of Huayuan City,
花垣城有禮制
a princess's husband must wear
郡主的夫婿必須佩戴
a copper bracelet with the badge of the family
擁有家族徽記的銅環
to prove that he belongs to her.
以證歸屬
He can't take it off as long as he lives.
終身都不能取下
You want me to put on the copper bracelet of Huayuan City?
你是要我戴上花垣城的銅環
Exactly.
沒錯
But in Xuanhu City,
可在玄虎城
only servants and handymen will be labelled.
只有奴僕和雜役才會被標記區別
Besides, as far as I'm concerned,
而且據我所知
there hasn't been such a ritual in Huayuan City.
花垣城並沒有這項禮制
There is now.
現在有了
Starting from you.
從韓少君開始
I believe
不過我相信
if it's Pei Heng,
如果是換作裴恆的話
he'll say yes without hesitation.
他會毫不猶豫地答應
I'm wondering if you'll wear
不知玄虎少君是否願意
a copper bracelet for Qianqian.
為芊芊佩上銅環呢
What if I say no?
如果我說不願意呢
Now that you refuse
既然韓少君
to admit your relationship with Qianqian,
不願意承認與芊芊的關係
why bother staying married?
又何苦沉迷於這段婚姻呢
How about
不如就此了結
ending your marriage?
你和芊芊的這樁婚事吧
You're pushing me
你這是在逼我
to let it go first.
先放手
Han Shuo,
韓少君
think about it.
好好地思量一下吧
Your Highness,
郡主
I wonder what the Crown Princess said
也不知道少城主和蘇公子
to Mr. Su.
說了什麼
He hasn't been here for several days.
他都已經好幾天沒有來看看你了
They say
都說啊
male entertainers are heartless.
這歡場的男人薄情寡義
It's really the case.
果然如此
Su Mu is not that kind of person.
蘇公子不是那樣的人
Mother.
母親
Yuanyuan.
長姐
Chuchu.
二姐
Qianqian, you're here.
芊芊 你來了
Let's have a discussion.
我們一起商量一下
The Double Seventh Festival is approaching.
七夕將至
I plan to pick a gentle and kind man
我準備給沅沅
to be Yuanyuan's husband.
找一個溫良淑德的夫婿
Mother, don't worry about me.
母親 您不用替我費心了
These days,
近日來
I always felt exhausted.
我總是覺得困頓乏力
I'm feeling my age.
想到我也上了年紀
I can't always stay by your side.
不能一直陪著你們
So, I want to see all of you get married
所以我想在有生之年
in my remaining years.
看著你們成家立業
Chuchu,
楚楚
when Yuanyuan is married,
等沅沅的事定了
it'll be your turn.
下一個就輪到你了
Me? But I...
我 可我
But Chuchu has fallen in love with Han Shuo.
可是楚楚她已經喜歡上韓爍了
Mother,
母親
you'd better pick a guy for Chuchu first.
那您還是先給楚楚選吧
I'm not interested.
我沒興趣
Forget about it.
算了
I'd better get Yuanyuan and Su Mu's issue done first.
還是先解決沅沅跟蘇沐的問題吧
Yuanyuan,
長姐
you're afraid you can't pick the right guy, right?
你不就是怕選不到心儀的郎君嗎
I've got an idea.
我有一個法子
Let's throw an embroidered ball.
咱們拋繡球吧
Throw an embroidered ball?
拋繡球
Yuanyuan, trust me.
長姐 你信我
I have 1,000 ways
我有一千種辦法
to make sure Su Mu gets the ball.
讓蘇沐接到你的繡球
He won't show up.
他是不會來的
Don't you want to give it a try?
你就不想試試看嗎
If he shows up,
如果他來了
it means he likes you too.
不就正好說明他也喜歡你
Trust me.
你放心
At this Double Seventh Festival,
今年的七夕
there is no smoke of gunpowder
沒有硝煙漫天
but ebullition of joy.
只有喜氣洋洋
The rabbit is so cute.
兔兔那麼可愛
It'll be tasty if we use it to make Spicy Diced Rabbit.
要做成麻辣兔丁才好吃呀
Go pick it up.
那你去把它撿回來吧
Where are you?
在哪裡呀
Mr. Rabbit.
兔子兄
I'm sorry.
真是辛苦你了
Chuchu is such a good archer.
只能怪我二姐箭法精準
Do you want to be braised or steamed,
你是想紅燒還是想清蒸
or become Spicy Diced Rabbit?
或者做成麻辣兔丁
Let's go.
起
Chuchu, one rabbit is enough.
二姐 一隻兔子夠我吃了
I'm leaving if there is nothing else to do.
沒事我先走了
Han Shuo, you're a good archer.
少君真是好箭法
Second Princess, you're a better one.
那也不及二郡主箭法精準
Pitifully, I missed it.
可惜還是沒有射中
I'm wondering what you want.
不知二郡主想射什麼
We're hunting. Of course, I want my prey.
打獵 自然是來射獵物的
But Chen Qianqian is your younger sister.
陳芊芊可是你妹妹呀
She has long stopped treating me as her sister.
她早就不把我當姐姐了
Why do I need to consider her as mine?
我又何必再留戀姐妹之情
It seems you were not drunk
看來那天晚上
that evening.
二郡主沒有喝醉
Han Shuo,
韓爍
now that my mother has ordered Qianqian to divorce you,
如今母親已經命你和三妹和離
I can beg her
我可以去求母親
to let you marry me.
讓你與我成婚
I'll only stay with Chen Qianqian this life.
韓某此生非陳芊芊莫屬
But it's obvious
可外人一眼就能看出
Chen Qianqian doesn't like you at all.
陳芊芊她根本就不喜歡你
She's always changeable and self-willed.
她一向朝三暮四 任性妄為
I've seen too much about that since my childhood.
從小到大我看得太多
She's going to abandon you
如今她就要捨棄你
and marry Pei Heng.
去和裴恆成婚
Why do you still have illusions about her feelings for you?
你竟還對她抱有幻想
It seems you don't know Qianqian well.
看來二郡主不太瞭解芊芊
And you know even less about me.
更不瞭解我
Are you so dead set on following her?
你就真的對她這麼死心塌地嗎
If you aim at Qianqian again,
如果二郡主的箭再對準芊芊
I'll shoot
那韓某的第二支箭
my second arrow.
可就要射出去了
Sooner or later,
早晚有一天
you'll know she doesn't deserve it.
你會知道陳芊芊不值得
I shot this rabbit for you.
這是我給你打的兔子
How will you cook it?
你想怎麼吃
Miss Lin Qi, I don't eat rabbit.
林七小姐 我不吃兔肉
Take it back.
你拿回去吧
Chen Qianqian.
陳芊芊
Why are you here?
你來幹什麼
Qianqian,
芊芊
are you here to take a rabbit to me?
你給我送兔子來了
There is something you don't know.
這你就不知道了吧
Minister Pei doesn't eat rabbit.
裴司學他不吃兔肉
I do.
我吃
You just told me you didn't.
你剛才不是這麼跟我說的
Su Mu, put the rabbit away.
蘇沐 把兔子收起來
Did you decide to eat it
難不成吃個兔子
just because it's from her?
還要看它姓什麼
Chen Qianqian,
陳芊芊
you've made him
你已經連累得他
a topic of conversation for the whole city.
成了滿城的談資
How dare you come here and...
你還有什麼臉面繼續
You!
你
I have something to say to you.
我有話跟你說
Chen Qianqian!
陳芊芊
Su Mu,
蘇沐
why did you not help Yuanyuan
你最近為什麼沒有
with her rehabilitation recently?
去幫沅沅做復健了
You promised me
你不是跟我說好了
you'd take care of her.
要代我去照顧她嗎
Zi Nian always stays by her side.
大郡主身邊已經有梓年了
I'm not irreplaceable.
也不是非小的不可
It's not all about rehabilitation.
這不單單是復健的事
The two of you care about each other.
你們倆情投意合
Why don't you take the opportunity
為什麼不趁這個機會
to spend more time with her?
好好相處相處
Your Highness, please don't say that.
少城主慎言
I'm a man of low origin. How dare I do that?
小的身份卑微 不敢僭越
If others know about it,
這讓外人聽見
the Princess Royal will be discredited.
有損大郡主清譽呀
Your Highness,
還請少城主
please don't mention this issue again.
不必多言
If you don't tell her how you feel about her,
你要是不去表白
how can she be determined to throw an embroidered ball?
沅沅她怎麼下定決心繡球選婿啊
Mealtime.
開飯了
Anybody? Guards! Someone broke out of prison!
來人哪 快來人 有人越獄了
Come out!
出來吧
Your Highness.
見過二郡主
Su Ziying?
蘇子嬰
I'm here to assist you.
小人自願前來輔佐二郡主
Assist me?
輔佐我
Haven't you been imprisoned?
你不是被問罪了嗎
How did you escape?
怎麼逃出來的
Chen Qianqian is infamous.
少城主失德
She doesn't deserve to be the future City Owner.
不配做花垣城城主
Your Highness, don't you want to replace her
二郡主 您難道不想取而代之
and enjoy the highest position
享受一人之下
and supreme power?
萬人之上的權力嗎
She's been elected as the Crown Princess.
少城主之位已經塵埃落定
It has nothing to do with me.
和我沒有什麼關係了
It all depends on human effort, Your Highness.
事在人為 二郡主
I'm confident that
小人有信心
I can help you
可助二郡主
become the Crown Princess.
奪得少城主之位
While you worked for Chen Qianqian,
你此前輔佐少城主
you reported she illegally possessed the defense map
卻揭發她私藏城防圖
and tried to rebel.
意圖不軌
And in the end,
不僅如此
instead of getting her into trouble,
舉報之事還未辦成
you were thrown into prison.
反害自己鋃鐺入獄
What can you do
你有什麼本事
to be my aide?
能做我的幕僚
I've got some secret information.
小人獲得一線報
The envoys of Xuanhu City
玄虎城使者來訪
have taken lots of explosives here.
他們攜帶大量火藥
They'll launch an attack
趁七夕佳節
in the evening of the Double Seventh Festival.
全城花燈夜 發難起兵
Do you have evidence?
你有何證據
I got this tip-off by accident
這封密信
in Chen Qianqian's mansion
是小人在陳芊芊府上潛伏時
when I worked for her.
偶然截獲
If you believe me,
郡主若信我
you can take the opportunity to arrest Han Shuo
就可以趁機擒獲韓爍
and use it as an excuse to accuse Chen Qianqian
以此連坐陳芊芊
so that she will be dethroned.
廢除她少城主之位
If you don't believe me,
郡主若不信我
you can throw me into prison again.
那就將我重新投入牢獄
Why do you want to help me?
可你為何要幫我
Your Highness, do you really forget me?
郡主 您真的不記得嬰嬰了
How dare you try to be hired as a lieutenant
你冒充自己是女子
by pretending to be a girl.
想要考取副將
I'll beat you to death.
我打死你
Qianqian, stop it.
芊芊 芊芊 別打了
Your Highness.
二郡主
Are you okay?
你沒事吧
I'll take you to the doctor.
我帶你去看大夫
You were the one who stopped Chen Qianqian
是您攔下了陳芊芊
and saved my life.
救了小人一命
You also let me heal my wounds at the Pei's Mansion.
還將小人送到裴府養傷
At that time,
自那以後
I made a promise that I'd pay you back.
小人立誓要報答二郡主
Thinking back carefully,
仔細回想
I did do this thing.
確實有過這件事
I admire you from the bottom of my heart.
小人對二郡主一片真心
I'll remain loyal to you.
日月可鑑
You just said
你剛剛說
Han Shuo and the envoys
韓爍與玄虎城使者
had arranged troops in ambush and laid explosives.
竟然私藏伏兵和火藥
Yes, Your Highness.
是的 二郡主
As long as you prove
您只要證實
Han Shuo intends to conquer Huayuan City,
韓爍意圖攻佔花垣城
you'll be able to turn the tables.
就能逆風翻盤
In this case,
如此一來
Han Shuo will definitely lose his life.
韓爍豈不是死定了
But you'll become the Crown Princess with ease.
但城主之位 唾手可得
I serve as the Minister of Defense,
我雖擔任司軍一職
but I couldn't move City Guards without letting my mother know.
卻無法瞞著母親動用護城軍
How can I cope with Han Shuo
又如何在母親不知情的前提下
while hiding it from her?
與韓爍對抗
There is one family in the city
城中有一府邸
whose security guards are brave and battle-wise.
府兵個個驍勇善戰 以一敵十
Do you mean the Pei family?
你是說 裴府裴恆
Pei Heng will help me?
他會幫我
I've already messed up once.
我之前已經失手一次
If I fail again this time,
這次若再不成功
I'll never win my mother's trust back.
就再也得不到母親的信任了
Minister Pei,
司學
this is a secret action,
此次行動必須暗中進行
so I have to ask you for a favor.
所以才會找你幫忙
Borrow soldiers?
借兵
Your Highness, as the Minister of Defense,
二郡主是司軍
you can move troops anytime.
手下有隨時可以調用的人馬
Why do you want to borrow my security guards?
為何要向我借兵
You said
你說韓爍
Han Shuo intended to conquer Huayuan City.
意圖攻佔花垣城
Do you have evidence?
又有何根據
I've investigated Xuanhu's envoys in secret
我已暗中查訪了玄虎使者
and confirmed the information is correct.
確認線報準確無誤
I've marked the locations
埋放火藥的炸點
where explosives have been laid.
我已標註在此
To avoid alerting the enemy,
只是不能打草驚蛇
I'm afraid I can't provide more evidence.
無法向你提供更多證據
Minister Pei,
司學
as for this matter,
此事寧可信其有
it's better to err on the side of caution.
不可信其無
You also want to prove to Qianqian that
你不是也想向芊芊證明
Han Shuo has an ulterior motive, right?
韓爍身懷異心嗎
As long as we join hands,
只要我們聯手
Han Shuo's plan will be destroyed
既可以破壞韓爍的計劃
and Qianqian will awaken to the truth.
又可以讓芊芊幡然醒悟
Why not do it?
何樂而不為呢
It's about the defense of the city.
城防大事
I have to report it to the City Owner.
還是要稟告城主
Don't you hope that
你難道不想讓芊芊
Qianqian can't find any excuse to refuse you?
再也無法推拒與你的婚事嗎
If I lend soldiers to you,
我借人給你
do you have confidence that you can catch Han Shuo?
你就有萬全把握 拿住韓爍
Young Master Han, if you're ready,
韓少君若是準備好了
I'll ask the blacksmith to get started.
那 便讓匠人動手了
I have to make things clear beforehand.
不過事先 我要說清楚
The bracelet is like shackles.
這手鐲跟鐐銬一樣
Once it's welded,
一旦焊死
it's impossible to take it off without leaving serious injuries.
不傷筋動骨 很難取下
Will the City Owner recall the order
是不是接受了你們的折辱
and never mention Qianqian's engagement to Pei Heng
城主就收回成命
as long as I accept the humiliation?
不再提及芊芊與裴恆的婚約
Please mind your language.
少君慎言
How can you consider the badge of Huayuan City
這花垣城的徽記
as a humiliation?
怎能說是折辱
If you're unwilling to do that,
少君若是不願
just tell the City Owner
那便與城主說清
you agree to divorce the Crown Princess.
說你願意同少城主和離
Do you want to scald him to death?
你們這是要活活燙死我們少君嗎
Stop there.
站住
What a coincidence.
好巧啊
Tomorrow is the Double Seventh Festival.
明天七夕節
You want to ask me to go out?
約我是嗎
I'm busy tomorrow.
我明天很忙
I need to arrange my mother's inspection on a festooned vehicle
明天要安排母親花車遊街的慶典
and help Yuanyuan with the ceremony of throwing an embroidered ball.
還要操持沅沅拋繡球的儀式
I really have no time left.
真的一點時間都沒有
Enjoy yourself tomorrow.
你明天好好玩
I have something to say to you.
我有話對你說
No matter what you want to say,
有什麼話
wait till the day after tomorrow.
過了明天之後再說
I'm going back.
我先回房
Can't you let me finish my words?
你能不能聽我把話說完
Why do you keep avoiding me?
為什麼你總是躲著我
Why do you always brush me off?
為什麼總是敷衍我
Why do you pay no attention to how I feel?
為什麼絲毫不在意我的感受
You made me
難道我對你的真心
feel so worthless.
就這麼一文不值
Your mother asked you to divorce me.
城主下令和離
You haven't given me an explanation.
你至今沒有給我一個解釋
Everyone wants us to get a divorce,
所有人都不希望我跟你在一起
but I insist on staying with you like a fool.
而我像個傻子一樣一意孤行
If you treat me like that,
如果連你都這樣的話
how could I persuade myself to keep going?
你讓我如何堅持下去
Then give up.
那就不要堅持了
What did you say?
你說什麼
Repeat it.
你再說一遍
All you know is scaring me
你只會嚇唬我
and threatening me.
要挾我
I threaten you?
我要挾你
It turns out I became the one
原來夫妻一場
who forced you to marry me.
變成我逼迫你了
You're free to go.
你走吧
Young Master.
少君
Young Master, you asked us to come here
少君叫我們來
because you've changed your mind, right?
是不是回心轉意了
Now that you've laid explosives
既然你們已經揹著我
all over the city behind my back,
把全城的爆炸點都安置好了
I have no choice but to do this.
箭在弦上 不得不發
Okay. Great.
好 好啊
These are all the locations with explosives?
這就是全城的爆炸點
Young Master, don't worry.
少君放心
Nothing will go wrong.
保證萬無一失
Only when you are one-up
只有成為人上人
can you get everything you want,
才能得到您想要的一切
including Chen Qianqian.
包括花垣城的陳芊芊
These musicians the Music and Dance Academy just bought
教坊司重新採買的
are not bad.
這批樂人不錯嘛
Exactly.
是不錯
Let's go.
走
Isn't that Lu Peng?
那不是陸鵬嗎
Has he been back?
他回教坊司了
Now that Su Mu has left the Academy,
那蘇沐離開教坊司
Lu Peng will be the best musician here.
這花魁的名號就是陸鵬的
Stop looking.
別看了 別看了
The best is yet to come.
一會兒有更熱鬧的呢
Really?
是嗎
The Princess Royal will throw an embroidered ball.
大郡主拋繡球招夫婿
Whoever catches it
拋給誰呀
will marry her.
大郡主就和誰成婚
That's exciting.
這麼精彩
Let's go.
走
Okay.
快走快走
Is Su Mu there?
蘇沐來了嗎
Throw it.
扔啊
Crown Princess.
少城主
Throw it. Crown Princess.
快拋啊 少城主
Crown Princess, Su Mu hasn't shown up.
少城主 蘇沐都沒來
Will this really work?
你這招不會不管用吧
It just started. No hurry.
這才剛開始你著什麼急
I've sent for him.
我已經派人去請了
Even if he comes,
可就算是他來了
how do you guarantee he can catch the ball?
你怎麼能確保蘇沐能接到繡球
Trust me. Yuanyuan, I've got everything arranged.
放心吧 長姐 早有安排
Zi Rui.
梓銳
Here.
來
In a while,
這一會兒啊
I'll approach Su Mu
我拿著這個繡球
with this embroidered ball.
偷偷地走到蘇沐的身邊
You need to pose like you're going to throw the ball,
你做一個拋繡球的姿勢
but don't really do it.
但是不要真拋
Cover it with your sleeve like this
你用袖子一擋
and people will think you've thrown it.
別人就以為你真的拋出去了
Then I'll pass this ball
然後我再把這個繡球
to Su Mu in secret.
偷偷地遞給蘇沐
Nobody will find it out.
這樣一來 神不知鬼不覺
Does it really work?
這 這能行嗎
Yes. Definitely. It's...
能行 肯定能行 這個叫
It's called editing thinking.
這叫剪輯思維
Let me show you.
我給你示範一下
I got it!
接到了
Got it?
明白了嗎
Just show them
我們給大家看一個
how you pose to throw an embroidered ball
你往外拋繡球的姿勢
and how Su Mu poses to catch it.
再加上一個蘇沐接到繡球的姿勢
Then everyone will think you've thrown a ball
大家在眼裡就是你拋了繡球
and Su Mu has caught it.
蘇沐接到了
That's it.
這事就成了
Okay!
好
There he is. Mr. Su is there.
來了來了 蘇公子來了
Mr. Su is there.
蘇公子來了
Hurry.
快快快
He's really there.
他真的來了
Princess Royal.
大郡主 大郡主
Yuanyuan, I'm going down to see Su Mu.
長姐 我現在就下去找蘇沐
Look carefully.
你看著
Throw the embroidered ball
一會兒我到蘇沐旁邊之後
after I'm by Su Mu's side.
你再扔繡球
Don't do it
要是我沒有到
before that.
你可千萬不要扔
Got it?
明白了嗎
Got it.
明白
We've been waiting so long.
我們等你好久了
Princess Royal.
大郡主
Isn't that Su Mu?
這不是蘇沐嗎
Is he also there to catch the embroidered ball?
難道他也是來搶繡球的
He's just a musician.
他可是個樂人
The Princess Royal is out of his league.
也想配大郡主
Maybe he's just here as a looker-on.
興許只是來看熱鬧
The Princess Royal is a cripple.
那大郡主還是個瘸子呢
Why is she out of his league?
有何配不得
Su Mu is the best musician, anyway.
他蘇沐 好歹也是個花魁呀
Maybe the Princess Royal just deserves a musician
說不定就是因為大郡主是個瘸子
now that she's a cripple.
才配了個樂人
Unbelievable.
還真有啊
Yeah.
是啊
Nothing is impossible.
有什麼配不得
Even Young Master Han wears a copper bracelet.
連韓少君都戴手環呀
Usually, only the underclass and servants
那可是低等下人 奴役
wear that thing.
才戴的東西
Young Master of Xuanhu is just so so.
玄虎少君不過如此
What bracelet were you talking about?
你們剛剛說什麼手環
Crown Princess, it has spread the whole city
少城主 今天城裡都傳遍了
that Han Shuo was ordered by the City Owner
韓少君奉城主之命
to wear a copper bracelet
為您佩戴手環
to prove he belongs to you.
以示歸屬
It means women of Huayuan City
說咱們花垣城的女人
can enslave men of Xuanhu City.
可以奴役玄虎城的男人
Wearing a bracelet?
戴手環
I didn't write it.
這段不是我寫的
Everyone wants us to get a divorce,
所有人都不希望我跟你在一起
but I insist on staying with you like a fool.
而我像個傻子一樣一意孤行
If you treat me like that,
如果連你都這樣的話
how could I persuade myself to keep going?
你讓我如何堅持下去
Han Shuo.
韓爍
Crown Princess. Have a rest.
少城主 歇會兒
Where is Han Shuo?
韓爍 韓爍呢
Han Shuo?
韓爍
I haven't seen him the whole day.
我一天都沒有看見他
Where has he gone?
他做什麼去了
Don't worry.
你別 彆著急啊
We'll find him.
咱們慢慢找
I shouldn't have refused him yesterday.
我昨天為什麼要拒絕他
He's so proud and arrogant.
他這麼心高氣傲的一個人
He must be heartbroken.
此刻不知道心裡有多難過呢
It's all my fault.
都是因為我
If it hadn't been for me,
要不是因為我
he couldn't have put on that damned bracelet.
他才不會戴什麼鬼手環
I let him down time and again.
我只會一而再再而三地寒他的心
Bracelet?
手環
Young Master Han put on a bracelet?
韓少君戴手環了
Uh. Don't be sad.
不是 你別太傷心呀
I don't think
我覺得吧
Young Master Han will take it to heart.
韓少君不會把這件事放在心上的
Well, this morning,
不是 我今早
I saw Bai Ji and Young Master Han
我碰到白芨和韓少君
ordering guys from Xuanhu City
指揮著玄虎城的人
to move a lot of boxes.
搬了好多箱子
Bai Ji told me
白芨還說
Young Master Han would give you
今天晚上韓少君要給你一場
a big surprise tonight.
大大的驚喜
He said, after tonight,
說過了今晚
you would regret
你肯定特別後悔
you treated Young Master Han like that.
之前那麼對待韓少君
They asked me not to tell you
他們不讓我告訴你
because they're afraid you won't feel surprised.
怕你提前知道
They've prepared special local products of Xuanhu City.
專門從玄虎城運過來的特產
Zi Rui,
梓銳
do you know what Xuanhu City abounds in?
你知道玄虎城的特產是什麼嗎
Fruit?
水果
Ironware?
鐵器
What is it?
那是什麼呀
Explosives.
炸藥
The boxes are filled with explosives.
箱子裡全是炸藥
After being pushed by my mother and refused by me,
韓爍被母親逼迫 被我推拒
he wants to bomb Huayuan.
他這是要炸了花垣城
Xuanhu will destroy Huayuan.
玄虎滅花垣
Crown Princess, don't run.
少城主 你別跑啊
Crown Princess, where are you going?
少城主 你去哪兒呀
The embroidered ball.
繡球
Right. The embroidered ball.
對對對 繡球
Zi Rui, keep the embroidered ball.
梓銳 護著這個繡球
Don't give it to anyone except Su Mu.
除了蘇沐 誰也別給
I have to find Han Shuo.
我去找韓爍
You lead a team respectively and split up.
各領一路人馬 分頭行動
Got it.
是
Your Highness,
稟告二郡主
our guys are
我們的人
lying in ambush at places
已經在韓爍佈置的各個爆炸點
where explosives have been laid.
埋伏開了
It seems you don't know Qianqian well.
看來二郡主不太瞭解芊芊
And you know even less about me.
更不瞭解我
If you aim at Qianqian again,
如果二郡主的箭再對準芊芊
I'll shoot
那韓某的第二支箭
my second arrow.
可就要射出去了
Once Han Shuo takes action,
一旦韓爍有所行動
arrest him at once.
就立刻將其抓捕
Try your best to capture him alive.
儘量留活口
Yes, Your Highness.
是 郡主
When Han Shuo is convicted,
等韓爍落實了罪名
he'll be at your disposal.
還不是任您發落
Chuchu.
楚楚
Crown Princess, you can't go in.
少城主 您不能進去
Go away!
走開
Chuchu, there is an urgency.
楚楚 我現在有要緊的事情
Only you can help me.
現在只有你能幫我了
What can I do for you?
我能幫你什麼
As the Crown Princess, you're awe-inspiring.
如今少城主好大的氣派
You even broke into my house
我星梓府竟是你說闖
without permission.
就能闖進來的
Han Shuo wants to conquer Huayuan City.
韓爍要攻佔花垣城
Send City Guards to find him.
你趕緊派護城軍去搜
We must stop him.
一定要阻止他
How did you know that?
你怎麼知道
There is no time to lose.
來不及了
Han Shuo had explosives laid in the whole city.
韓爍在全城埋下了炸藥
Mother's inspection tour is about to start.
母親的花車馬上要開始遊街
Once the explosives are ignited...
一旦他引爆炸藥
He won't have his way.
他不會得手的
I've sent guys to lie in ambush
我已經派人守好了
at every place with explosives.
他安排的每一個爆炸點
You've already known that?
你早就知道了
You've not only known that,
你不僅知道了
but also sent guys to catch him.
你還 你還派人蹲他
Han Shuo harbors evil designs.
韓爍意圖不軌
As the Minister of Defense,
我身為花垣城司軍
I have to arrest him.
自然要捉拿他
To convict someone, you must catch him red-handed.
捉賊捉贓
I'll give him a deadly blow tonight.
我今晚必定一擊即中
You knew what he was going to do today.
你明明知道他今日計劃
Why did you not stop him?
你為什麼不攔住他
Instead, you want to see him make big trouble.
還要看著他發生今日大禍
Chen Chuchu,
陳楚楚
to become the Crown Princess,
你為了想要坐上少城主的位置
you even decided to give up Han Shuo?
連韓爍都不要了嗎
You don't have the right to yell at me.
你有什麼資格在我面前叫囂
Why does Han Shuo want to conquer Huayuan?
韓爍為什麼要攻城
Isn't it because you keep changing your mind
難道不是你朝三暮四
and have so many love affairs?
拈花惹草逼的他
Chuchu, stop it.
楚楚 住口
Don't make things difficult for Qianqian.
不要為難芊芊
Pei Heng,
裴恆
you can help me, right?
你可以幫我的 對不對
Go find him and stop him.
你去找他 你去阻止他
As the son of the former Minister of Defense,
你是裴司軍的兒子
you can help me out.
你一定可以幫我的
Why does he have to do that?
憑什麼人人都要幫你
Today is the Double Seventh Festival.
今日七夕遊街
City Guards need to patrol the whole city
護城軍有巡城任務
and protect our mother.
還要維護母親的安全
Why don't you have a guess?
不如你猜猜
Who lent me soldiers
派去圍剿韓爍的人馬
to encircle and suppress Han Shuo?
是誰借給我的
Fine.
好
Neither of you is obliged to help me,
你們都沒有義務要幫我
but I can't do nothing
但是我也不能眼睜睜地
while watching you give up on Han Shuo.
看你們這樣放棄韓爍
Now that you don't go,
你們不去
I'll go alone.
我一個人去
I can stop Han Shuo by myself.
我一個人也可以攔著韓爍
Guards!
來人
Now that you're here, you'd better stay.
既然來了就別走了
I'll keep our mother company.
我去陪母親巡城
Just stay here.
你就好好待在這裡
I'll deal with you later.
等著事後發落吧
Chen Chuchu,
陳楚楚
didn't you say you wanted Han Shuo?
你不是說你要韓爍的嗎
Pei Heng.
裴恆
Don't look at me like that.
你別這樣看著我
I know you're not that type of person.
我知道你不是這樣的
You couldn't hurt others.
你不可能害人的
When will she throw it?
還不拋啊
Come on.
真是
When will she do it?
怎麼還不扔啊
Is she going to do it or not?
拋不拋了
It's an important event in her life.
畢竟是終身大事
It's understandable she's cautious.
謹慎點 正常
I've been waiting for two hours.
我都等了一個時辰了
If it goes on like this, it'll be dawn.
再等下去 天都要亮了
Is she going to throw it or not?
到底拋不拋啊
Mr. Su is back.
蘇公子又回來了
It's not Mr. Su.
不是蘇公子
Hurry up.
快點啊
He won't show up again.
他不會再來了
Excuse me.
來 讓一讓
Help me with it.
幫我擋著點
Guo,
過兒
did you see Mr. Su?
看見蘇公子沒
No.
沒有啊
What does he look like?
不過 蘇公子長什麼樣來著
Your Highness, how about you don't throw it today?
郡主 要不咱今天不拋了
Let's go back.
咱回府吧
They all want to make a decision for me.
他們都想替我做決定
I'm a cripple,
難道我身為一個廢人
so I even don't have the right
連為自己終身大事
to decide who I can marry?
做決定的權利都沒有嗎
No. I'll throw it.
不 我要拋
Why do I have to give up just because he doesn't show up?
他不來 我便不成婚了嗎
Pass the ball to me.
把繡球給我
Your Highness.
郡主
Pass it to me.
給我
Her Majesty has left her mansion
城主的花車
on the festooned vehicle.
已經出府開始遊街了
We've missed the auspicious time.
咱都已經錯過吉時了
How about we don't do it today?
要不咱不拋了
Let's go back.
咱回去吧
Guo, the Crown Princess
過兒 咱少城主說了
asked the Princess Royal not to throw the embroidered ball
蘇公子沒來
unless Mr. Su shows up.
不讓大郡主拋繡球
Wait here.
你在這兒等著
I'll go stop her.
我上去攔住她
Your Highness, throw it!
郡主 快拋啊
Here. Your Highness.
這邊 大郡主
Look. She threw it.
看啊 拋了
She threw it.
拋了
It's here.
來了來了
Here. It's mine.
這邊 我的我的
The ball.
球 球
Meng Guo, get the ball!
孟過 搶球
It's mine.
給我
Mine.
我的 我的 我的
It'll be mine.
我要拿到了
Stop pushing.
別擠呀你
I got it!
我搶到了
Where is it?
在哪啊
Don't grab.
別搶啊
Who dares to grab?
我看你們誰敢搶
You? You?
你搶 你搶
He got the embroidered ball.
他拿到繡球了
He'll be the Princess Royal's husband.
郡主的夫婿就是他
It's him.
是他
I can't believe he got it.
竟讓他給拿著了
A musician.
一個樂人
He's a musician.
他是個樂人
Your Highness,
大郡主
he's the one who got the embroidered ball.
這位便是搶到繡球的人
Your Highness, let me pay my respects.
參見郡主
Tell everyone
傳我令
he'll be my husband now that he got the embroidered ball.
搶到繡球的人就是我的夫婿
I'm determined to marry a musician.
我偏嫁樂人
Got it.
是
I'll look for Han Shuo with you,
我帶你去找韓爍
but you have to promise me
但你要答應我
this is your last time being bewitched by him.
這是你最後一次受他蠱惑
You can't believe him again
以後無論他任何花言巧語
no matter what he says.
你都不能再相信他
I'll stop him.
我會攔住他的
I won't let him do that.
我不會讓他這麼做的
No way. We couldn't find him if it goes on like this.
不行 我們這樣根本找不到
We'd better get off the horse and act separately.
我們還是下馬分頭找吧
Here.
這兒呢
I heard you were looking everywhere for me.
聽人說你滿城在找我
Where did you go?
你跑哪兒去了
I've been looking for you so long.
我找了你好久
I did something great.
當然是去做大事了
Your timing is perfect. I was planning to look for you.
正好 我正派人去尋你了
Even if you didn't want to see me,
就算你今天不想見我
I'd tie you up and take you there.
我綁也得把你綁過去
The City Owner is here!
城主來了
Mother.
母親 母親
Qianqian.
芊芊
I'll show you something interesting.
我要讓你看一個有趣的東西
Wait. Han Shuo.
等一下 韓爍
It's my fault.
是我不好
I shouldn't have ignored you.
我不該不理你
I shouldn't have brushed you off.
不該敷衍你
I shouldn't have pushed you away.
不該把你推給別人
I promise I won't do that again.
我保證我以後都不會再這麼做了
Han Shuo, I like you.
韓爍 我喜歡你
I really like you.
我真的喜歡你
I want to stay with you.
我想跟你在一起
I'll stay with you
不管誰來阻止我
no matter who wants to stop me.
我都要跟你在一起
Why are you saying these silly words?
你說什麼傻話呢
I know I let you down.
我覺得我對不起你
You even suffered this for me.
你為了我受了這麼大的委屈
It couldn't be taken off, right?
這是不是摘不下來了
It can't as long as you live, right?
一輩子都摘不下來了
I don't think it's a badge of Huayuan City.
我不覺得這是你們花垣城的徽記
I think...
我覺得
... it's you.
這是你呀
You're a rose with thorns.
我把你這朵帶刺的花戴在身上
Wearing a rose doesn't make me suffer.
怎麼能算是委屈呢
You hurt me
雖然
with your thorns,
你總是刺我
but I
但我
love it.
心裡歡喜
I'll stay here
我願意為了你
for you.
留在這兒
I'll stay by your side all my life.
一輩子都留在你身邊
For my sake,
那你可不可以為了我
can you stop...
不要管花
Your Majesty!
城主 城主 城主
Your Majesty. Your Highness.
城主 二郡主
Han Shuo, don't!
韓爍 不要